<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ayako Tsuchiyama | Tectonophysics</title>
    <link>https://eqsci.mit.edu/tecto/author/ayako-tsuchiyama/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://eqsci.mit.edu/tecto/author/ayako-tsuchiyama/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Ayako Tsuchiyama</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://eqsci.mit.edu/tecto/images/logo.svg</url>
      <title>Ayako Tsuchiyama</title>
      <link>https://eqsci.mit.edu/tecto/author/ayako-tsuchiyama/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tectonophysics at the Slow-to-Fast Earthquakes workshop!</title>
      <link>https://eqsci.mit.edu/tecto/post/meeting_japan_sep2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eqsci.mit.edu/tecto/post/meeting_japan_sep2022/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div id=&#34;r-markdown&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://eqsci.mit.edu/tecto/author/louise-maubant/&#34;&gt;Louise&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://eqsci.mit.edu/tecto/author/caroline-mouchon/&#34;&gt;Caroline&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://eqsci.mit.edu/tecto/author/william-b.-frank/&#34;&gt;William&lt;/a&gt; went to the NASA Solid Earth Team meeting, a biennial meeting for the Earth Surface and Interior program at NASA. &lt;a href=&#34;https://eqsci.mit.edu/tecto/author/louise-maubant/&#34;&gt;Louise&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://eqsci.mit.edu/tecto/author/caroline-mouchon/&#34;&gt;Caroline&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://eqsci.mit.edu/tecto/author/william-b.-frank/&#34;&gt;William&lt;/a&gt; each presented posters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intermediate-depth earthquakes</title>
      <link>https://eqsci.mit.edu/tecto/research/intermediate-depth_earthquakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eqsci.mit.edu/tecto/research/intermediate-depth_earthquakes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How deep do earthquakes occur on Earth? Deep earthquakes, generally defined as earthquakes
deeper than 70 km, are generated in a deeper portion of subduction slabs where the extremely
high pressures and temperatures make frictional slip unlikely. Seismicity in the deep Earth can
provide essential information on the physical processes that control fluid distribution within the
mantle, yet the mechanism of deep earthquakes is still enigmatic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deep earthquakes are categorized into two groups depending on the depth. Intermediate-depth
earthquakes generally occur at the depth range of 70-300 km, then deep-focus earthquakes
continue from 300 km.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our research group, we focus on intermediate-depth earthquakes in Colombia. The region
shows “a nest of earthquakes” where intermediate-depth earthquakes densely occur within the
10-km cube. The Bucaramanga Nest in Colombia is one of the most productive areas of
intermediate-depth earthquakes on Earth. We are curious about the mechanism of triggering
many earthquakes in a limited volume within subduction slabs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, we are working on building a systematic catalog of earthquakes in the Bucaramanga
Nest. The goal of our initial project is to detect smaller events that have not been identified in the
original catalog by SGC to understand the background seismicity. After completing the catalog
making, we will work on spectral analyses to find differences between regular earthquakes in
shallow regions, slow-slip events in subduction zones, and other deep earthquakes in different
regions. By comparing the source spectra, we will identify the fundamental mechanism of deep
earthquakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ayako was previously working on deep-focus earthquakes in Japan. After joining William’s
group, she widely pursues her curiosity about deep earthquakes. She considers a key to revealing
the mechanism of deep earthquakes buried in not only subduction zones on Earth but also other
planetary bodies such as the Moon, Mars, and even Titan. All those planets have/will have
installed man-made seismometers, and she hopes to work on those seismic data in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
