<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eric Beaucé | Tectonophysics</title>
    <link>https://eqsci.mit.edu/tecto/author/eric-beauce/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://eqsci.mit.edu/tecto/author/eric-beauce/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Eric Beaucé</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://eqsci.mit.edu/tecto/images/logo.svg</url>
      <title>Eric Beaucé</title>
      <link>https://eqsci.mit.edu/tecto/author/eric-beauce/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>BPMF: A backprojection and matched-filtering workflow for automated earthquake detection and location</title>
      <link>https://eqsci.mit.edu/tecto/publication/beauce-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eqsci.mit.edu/tecto/publication/beauce-2023/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systematic Detection of Clustered Seismicity Beneath the Southwestern Alps</title>
      <link>https://eqsci.mit.edu/tecto/publication/beauce-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eqsci.mit.edu/tecto/publication/beauce-2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FastMatchedFilter (FMF)</title>
      <link>https://eqsci.mit.edu/tecto/software/fmf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eqsci.mit.edu/tecto/software/fmf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Matched-filter searches are an important tool in modern seismology to detect seismic events.
They operate via an algorithm that computes the correlation coefficient between a template event and a sliding window of continuous seismic records.
A detection is recorded when the correlation coefficient crosses an established threshold.
We present an optimized program, called Fast Matched Filter (FMF), that efficiently runs a network-based matched-filter search with either central processing units (CPUs) or Nvidia graphics processing units (GPUs).
Wrappers for both Python and MATLAB (CPU only) are pro- vided to easily run FMF on a wide range of computational resources, from multicore laptops to specialized computing clusters with GPUs.
Both implementations leverage a significantly similar structure when it comes to the continuous com- putation of correlation coefficients in the time domain to achieve rapid performance.
The highly parallel architecture of GPUs lends itself perfectly to the matched-filter algorithm, and we achieve the fastest run times with our GPU implementation.
FMF allows for seismic network-based matched-filtering between a large set of template waveforms and a large continuous dataset in a reasonable amount of time.
Such fast run times are an important step in expanding the scope of earthquake detection and fostering the reproducibility of such studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you use FMF in your own research, please reference the above article.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fast matched-filter (FMF): an efficient seismic matched-filter search for both CPU and GPU architectures</title>
      <link>https://eqsci.mit.edu/tecto/publication/beauce-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eqsci.mit.edu/tecto/publication/beauce-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
